Christopher Hines

+49 152 2687 4263 | chrishinesabdn@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a practical person with an aptitude for learning and developing new skills. I do not shy away from responsibility and endeavour to complete every challenge to the best of my ability.

With over 5 years of industry experience in software design, development, testing, and deployment I am confident in producing and delivering quality products across a wide variety of markets.

I consider myself to be a calm, approachable person that thrives while learning from others, however, being a self-motivated individual I often perform with minimal supervision while maintaining a high standard of work.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer @ Skoove

October 2017 - January 2020

- Mobile application (React Native + Objective-C) development role.
- Additional responsibilities included the continuous integration, deployment, and release of products.
- Played a key role in an agile, lean development and release cycle.

<u>Software Developer</u> @ IMES International

July 2014 - September 2016

- Web (HTML + JavaScript, C# ASP.NET) and application (Python, Java) development role.
- Additional responsibilities included database management (SQL) and company IT infrastructure management.
- Involved in several software projects from design to delivery, in addition to several inherited projects.

In addition to my full-time experience I have also been involved in multiple short-term contract positions, and a number of personal projects pursued in my own time.

EDUCATION

2010 - 2014: University of Aberdeen BA (Hons) Computing Science

Modules included:

- Security
- Computational Intelligence
- Operating Systems
- Web Application Development
- Algorithmic Problem Solving

- Knowledge-based Systems
- Artificial Intelligence
- Enterprise Computing
- Data Management
- Human-computer Interaction

In my final year I carried out my honours project which produced a system capable of using natural language to describe workflow schematics to human users. The development of this project involved research, surveys, meetings with subject matter experts, and software design and development.

SKILLS

- JavaScript / React / React Native
- Python
- Java
- ASP.NET
- C#

- SQL Server / MySQL / SQLite
- Version control systems
- Software support + deployment
- Documentation writing
- SharePoint development + management

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Graphic design

I have a self-taught understanding of graphical editing software such as Photoshop, GIMP, and Paint.NET. This has proven useful when designing and creating graphical assets and user interfaces for software. In my previous positions I was often recruited to help with graphical design tasks or photo editing.

Music technology

I spend some of my spare time tinkering with various audio technology and software for my own enjoyment. This began when I initially started using Audacity to make personal mixes of my favourite music. After graduating I learnt how to use Ableton Live, and have more recently taken the time to understand different audio sources and codecs. I have also developed an understanding of transcoding and learnt how to use spectral analysis to compare releases for my music library.